I have millions of short-form content
followers, and I
must admit,
I think I've been late to the biggest
change that
I think has occurred in the short-form
content creation space.
It's happened right in front of us,
and I don't even think the majority of us
have
realized. And it was only
when I had a meeting with Meta last week
that it
confirmed my beliefs. In this video,
I'm going to explain to you the revolution
that is coming in short form content
creation.
I'll also explain why Declan,
my videographer, has quit.
But just before I get into that,
it's very important
that everyone watching this
realizes you are going to have to
represent your brand,
and probably with short
form to begin with,
later with long form down the line.
Going to put a guy on blast who I met in
Pret two weeks ago.
I'm in London.
We're outside Holborn Station.
We're giving out thousands of cans of New
Tonic.
Go into Pret for a little bit of lunch.
Guy comes over.
He's telling me about a Brazilian jujitsu
app that he's created with his business
partner. Wow.
Then he gives me a business card, branded.
Wow.
He even gives me a branded T-shirt. Great.
I said, "You're making content,
right?" And he goes, "Ah.
Yeah, I need to start that." I said,
"Excuse me,
why are you not creating content
yet for your brand? If this app is
that important and it's going to help
that many
jujitsu athletes,
why wouldn't you be telling people about
it?" He said he hadn't
got the confidence yet to create the
content.
I said, "Mate, are you fucking stupid?
You've just cold approached me to promote
your business in Pret while I'm
fucking eating my lunch,
and you're too scared to make content,
which you just put
on your phone and post to the Internet?
You've got this all fucked up, mate."
And I said to him, "The reason
that I'm never
going to invest in your business is
that you won't even show up for your
brand,
your app, your business,
yet you want me to?
In which deranged world does
that make sense?" I was like,
"You've got the courage
to come up in here and tell me about it,
but you haven't got the courage to make
content. Also,
in what world do you think it's more
important to have a branded
T-shirt and business cards than it
is to tell hundreds, maybe thousands,
or maybe
tens of thousands of people about what
you've built, what you've created?" Not to
mention that he should have done
that for months before the app
was even ready.
But anyway,
almost every single struggling business
that I work with don't really
realize what's happening.
You've got your offer.
Certain amount of people need to see it to
buy.
But for them to see your offer,
you need to have a certain amount of
contacts to
send your offer to,
and to have a certain amount of contacts
to send your offer to,
you need a certain amount of people aware
of your brand.
Typically, I find
that about 1% of my audience will buy from
me at any given point.
The other 99%,
we're either warming them up to purchase
or just going to let them
fuck off. Now, last week,
one of the businesses
that I've invested into recently,
Adapt BJJ, incredible jujitsu gear,
by the way. But don't take my word for it.
I own a significant chunk of the business.
We did a content shoot day where we
invited all of our best customers into
London.
We trained with them. We rolled with them.
We did a content shoot. We had a laugh.
We had pizza. We drank New Tonics. It
was an amazing day. I go home.
I'm laying in bed. It's 9:00 PM.
We have no content to show for it.
And so I go into the group chat
and I say to
everyone, "Yo,
where's the content from today?"
Everything was filmed on an
expensive high-grade camera.
The photographers had to color grade the
images.
The videographers had to upload everything
to their computers and color grade it.
We had nothing to show for an event where
100 people came to a community
event.
I realized we wouldn't get an edit out on
the day.
Why did we wait so long to get some
content?
Why didn't we just use our phones?
We could have put a reel together
that we could have posted,
and it would've took
five minutes.
I came to realize we're not moving fast
enough.
That edit needs to go out a few hours
after the event to create some
FOMO so that we can flip it
and do more events in the future.
Whereof which we get more people to the
event, we get more content, we get to put
it out there, we create more FOMO,
et cetera. So that
was in the back of my mind.
Any of you that watched this channel
before know that I will moan at people a
lot
where you seem to think you've made enough
content, and I'm here to remind you that
you haven't.
That exact same day we did the Adapt
filming day, I hit
5,000 Instagram posts. Now,
that's quite a lot if you think
about it,
but Instagram wasn't even my first
platform.
I was on Facebook before that. There
was a period where I
was posting on Facebook
and I wasn't posting on Instagram.
Before that, I was on WordPress.
Now, just to remind you,
even at 5,000 Instagram posts,
I still had an Amex bill this month
that made my sphincter and my
asshole twitch.
I'm not even out of the woods at 5,000
posts.
So the fact you think
that you're 124 posts on Instagram,
you're like, "Where's my
fucking Bugatti?" Some of you
are just mental.
For most of you,
it's going to take 500 posts to become
even semi-good at
making it seem like you know what you're
doing.
The majority of you,
it sounds crazy to say this,
are 200 to 300 posts away from
finding a rhythm. Now,
that meeting with Meta.
I have a contact at Facebook Meta. Yes,
I've got over a million
followers on the platform. But even then,
I'm one of their shittest creators.
I went in and met with them, asking them,
"What's going on?
What's trendy?" Blah, blah, blah.
And she says to me,
"Why can I not see on your Instagram
that you're posting
through edits?" And I was like, "Well,
I record the content.
I send it to my video guy, Declan.
He chops it up. He edits it.
He sends it back.
I post it." She was like, "Hmm."
And
without telling me
that I'd be getting more engagement
through the Edits app, it
kind of made sense.
Why did Instagram create the Edits app?
It's to give creators the ability to shoot
content, chuck on captions, chop the
fat,
and then you can push it quite literally
to the platform through that app.
I was like,
"I'm going to have to test this.
I'm going to have to try it." So over the
next few days, anytime we were shooting
content,
and I'm going to show you the performance
of that in a second, I told
Declan to put down his five grand camera.
Said, "Put that down.
You're going to shoot on my iPhone." I
took full control.
Said, "You go here, film this, do this,
get this, take that angle again, come back
around." Then I get my phone back,
and I could edit
that entire thing in about five
to seven minutes. Now,
he couldn't even color grade the footage
or even move it
from his camera to his laptop in the time
that I completed the entire edit.
Now,
would it have looked better on a camera?
Sure.
But I'm not sure that, one, the algorithm,
the Edits app,
or even two,
that people on Instagram right
now want to see perfectly curated content.
And how do I know? Well,
the answer's been right in front of me the
entire time.
One of the biggest levers
that we're pulling for New Tonic to make
millions every
month is something called UGC,
which stands for user-generated content.
Now,
if we look at a platform like TikTok Shop,
we could pay a celebrity to go on
there and endorse it, but actually,
there's two channels on TikTok Shop.
One, where you have affiliates.
They talk about the product.
They talk about the drink.
They then get an affiliate code.
They can sell on the platform
and get a bit of commission from us.
But then two, on the other end,
you might look to do something called CPM,
cost per
1,000 views.
And you might then pay people just to talk
about your product, have it
in their videos, whatever it is. That
is the way
... that sales online are going.
Some of our best-performing paid ads
aren't
super polished. In fact,
one right now generating a four
times return on ad spend
is filmed on iPhone.
So I've had all of these signals in front
of me for fucking months, yet I've been
attached to wanting to make super polished
content.
Have you even noticed how many content
creators have gone back to wired
headphones?
And I know the people doing this,
they're making $10 million a year.
The reason that they're talking into their
microphone while shooting on their phone
is they want to give
that non-professional look.
They could even use their back camera
instead of the front camera, but they want
this effect. Off the fly, high volume,
low effort,
perceived low effort content
is making a comeback.
We went through a lot of changes in
short-form content over the last few
years.
So we went from back in my day,
I had to manually type out every caption
on a
video. 2018,
it would take me 45 minutes to do a
90-second video,
just the captions.
Then during the pandemic,
we saw the TikTok-ification of social
media, where
content was shown to people interested in
your stuff, not people that follow you.
But then we went into this realm of hyper
over-edited
transitions, captions, B-roll,
and people are exhausted.
And now they kind of want to see a video
from someone that's like their friend or
something that's sent in a WhatsApp chat.
They want to be communicated to,
not like they're talking to a brand,
but a real
person. And people are now calling
that yap content.
But the reason that I don't particularly
like the term yap is yap insinuates
that what you have said has not been
cleverly planned, designed, or
strategically thought about beforehand.
Now, before that scares you
or intimidates you, there
is only one way you become
strategic and clever in the world of
content creation, and that is through
thousands of repetitions.
There is no book you can read. There
is no course you can do.
There is no fucking YouTube video out
there that is going to do anything more
than
you doing hundreds of repetitions of
something.
Having videos that you think
are going to do well bomb
and have videos that you
thought might bomb do well.
And anyone that tells you otherwise,
even my Short-Form
Content Mastery course, there's that.
Doing 1,000 fucking videos
is going to do way more for anything out
there than you
could ever fucking buy from me.
Get them both together.
Anyway,
now I'm going to show you some of the
results, and then I'll tell you why
Declan quit and why he's no longer working
with me.
But let's get through the results first.
So right here is my Instagram feed,
and this morning I
posted about- So you're not sure when to-
Our Focus Pouches,
61,000. Again,
you could say for the amount of followers
I have, that's not a
lot. But anyway, here,
super polished video.
So from that Reverse X,
I'm going to bump him for- 41,000.
See these three here,
this row right in the middle here.
When I arrived in Ireland, and by the way,
here's the edit that I got.
[upbeat music] Super polished, 68,000.
Whatever comes in front of me,
I love sniffing it out.
iPhone in the gym to show a technique,
103,000.
These three videos I made in Ireland.
All, just grab my phone, edit this,
have a look at this.
[upbeat music] Shot on iPhone, cut,
trim the fat,
640,000 views. The next one,
I shit you not, we
did this tractor shoot in a petrol
station.
What's the craic? What's the craic?
It took seven minutes to film,
took me three minutes to edit,
136,000. Then here, I saw a funny skit,
and I
literally in about three
or four minutes recorded this.
[piano music] Holding the can of Noatonic,
trying to get that bit of branding.
Declan didn't even film that.
[chuckles] Our UK
head of retail, James Cox,
who's never made a piece of content in his
life
video-wise or done an edit,
I just gave him my iPhone.
I said, "Hold this,
I'm going to walk into you." Now let me go
into the edits app,
and I'm going to show you how easy this
is.
So for instance,
if we go back to this video here.
I said to a guy that's working at Maxline
Designs, "Hey, can you film us from
the side?
I want to get us both looking at the car
happy with it." I then said to
him, "Can you come up close
and film me from in front?" So he then got
a shot of me
in front. I said, "Okay,
now go in front of him,
get a shot of him." I said, "Okay,
we're going to get in the car.
I want a shot from the side.
You do have to become a director here."
Then we get the footage of the car rolling
out. Now everything here
is chopped together, and it's very, very
quick to do it. Again,
with this video here, all I did
was just chop little bits away.
If we look at this tractor edit,
you'll notice
these are just different videos where I've
cut different bits, put bits of text,
and then I put a bit of music on the end.
The more you do this,
the better you get at it.
Okay, let's try and do this in real time.
A lot of people on the internet like to
say that there's not enough research about
the absorption of cognizin through the
mouth.
Take my finger off, leave it for a second,
take a breath.
[inhales]
But what they fail to realize
is the actual pouch,
we're not just getting the
absorption through the mouth.
And I fucked that one up,
so we're going to delete that,
and I'm going to start
again.
But what they don't realize
is we're not absorbing everything here
through the
mouth. That's just where we're putting it.
So what I want you to think about
is NeuroGum, which
is a very popular chewing gum
that has nootropics and caffeine in it.
Cool. Now it's zoomed into 1.2,
so I'm just going to zoom it back out to
one.
I'm going to grab one of... Actually,
let me get one of these.
Then I might even go for a slight scene
change.
I want you to imagine each one of these
being like a little teabag, and the
ingredients in that
when they mix with saliva,
go around our mouth.
And yes,
some will be absorbed through the mouth,
but the rest of it we're just
going to ingest,
and it's just going to go down our track
like something else,
whether it be pills,
whether it be powders.
The thing is, most nootropics,
here's cognizin,
our main active ingredient of the
pouches,
they need to be taken with a drink.
So unless you've got a drink with you,
you can't really do much.
And taking a pill without something
is probably going to give you some kind of
indigestion or at least some horrible
burps.
The pouches mean that all you need
is to have saliva.
And if you're well-hydrated,
that's not going to be a problem.
And you're probably thinking why I'm
making this video.
But ultimately, this video
is an educational piece where people may
not have
understood the true benefits of a pouch
versus other mediums.
And they could walk away from this
90-second video knowing everything.
So if you want to be able to have a
pick-me-up with productivity, with
nootropics, with caffeine,
without needing a drink,
so it could live in your pram
or under your armrest in your car,
check these out. Head to nootonic.com.
We have a five-pack for £25,
so one of these with 20 pucks in it
literally costs
£5 each. If you don't like it, email me,
james@nootonic, and I will refund you in
person. Then fuck
And the best part is you can get these
from the website, nutonic.com.
It's 25 pounds for five,
so it's literally five pounds a pack.
There's 20 pouches per pack, which
is a lot more than all of our competitors.
If you don't love it, email me,
james@nutonic.com, and I'll make it right.
Cool. So then from there,
the best thing I can give you as far as
advice for this would be go to captions,
and the fact that you can
generate caption,
which is automated,
I can't tell you the amount
of headaches that it's going to save you
from.
So you'll notice there
are gaps here between it.
Almost every time it makes sense to just
cut that, or you can drag it
closed.
People on the internet like to say
that there's not enough re-
So you see here,
just between the two of them,
I just can either cut that,
and these little gaps will be breathing
or where I've pressed the button and I'm
not sure it's recording yet.
The first thing I can recommend is
that you just cut
those bits. You line it up.
It looks like the captions have
not been perfect on this one, but this
is just an example.
And that is a one-minute reel
that I've done off the cuff.
Not going to edit the whole thing because
you guys will get bored.
And then from there,
I can actually save that for later
and actually edit it and
put it out later.
My time to generate that
was about two minutes.
My edit time would've taken about a
minute.
I can now export
that straight to Instagram.
A lot of people on the internet like to
say I know that Instagram are
going to reward me on that, and even
if you were to say to me, "Oh, but James,
now
is an optimal time to post." Well,
if I go down here to more options, I can
schedule the reel. So there
are no excuses for you to not create
pieces of content like this.
Now for me to get Declan,
to bring him here,
to set up the camera, to film,
to give him the memory card,
for him to go to edit
it and color grade it and upload it
and then export it,
then put it on Google Drive
and send it back. We
are not any longer in a position where
we have the time or luxury to do that.
If you have an idea, get it out.
If you want to say something, get it out.
You want to react to a piece of content,
get it out.
With the amount of options
that we now have,
all the barriers to creating content
are gone. The short-form game is changing,
and the beautiful thing
is you don't need more, you need less.
Now, there are going to be some caveats.
If you've got a podcast,
don't film it on an iPhone because you
will
need to get those clips or need to go up,
whatever.
And for long-form, I still think
that it's a good idea to have a good type
of
filming setup like this so you can hear me
well.
But I can record this video
and put it out in five days and it's fine.
But if you want to react to something,
if you've seen something online, if
something's said on TV
and you want to react to it,
that shouldn't take longer than
15 to 20 minutes max.
It's the world we're moving into.
That'll be your short-form content engine.
Long-form will be the same.
I arrive to the gym or my studio
or wherever you film.
I give myself 10 minutes to jot down some
notes of things I want to talk about.
I hit record on the camera.
I then get this, I export it,
I send it to my editor.
He then uploads it into YouTube.
We create some packaging for it.
It will go out.
That is a constant variable.
I do not see that changing for a long
time.
But short form, this is a revolution.
[phone clatters] Yap content
is going to be the future.
Film, add captions, chop the fat, export,
upload, and again,
inside there, there's a download button.
You want to download
that once you've posted it to Instagram.
Push it to LinkedIn, push it to TikTok,
push it to fucking Twitter, wherever you
want to put it. YouTube Shorts,
get it out there.
Do you know why they made trial reels?
Because people are scared of losing
followers.
And maybe that's why I've not been posting
as much short-form
recently. That could be it,
because I built an audience off doing fat
loss videos,
and I no longer talk about fat loss.
If I was to arrive at my business call to
give myself some advice, should I be
putting out super engaging content on a
really frequent basis, or shall I be doing
nothing hoping that my follower count
doesn't go down?
If anything,
getting from 1.4 to 1.3 million could be
the best thing that happens
to my business and my brand.
Trial reels are there for creators
that are so
petrified to lose followers from putting
out something different that they created
a whole new system for it.
But it's time to yap.
It's time to get out there in front of
your camera. User-generated content
is king.
For a fucking $100 million business like
Nutonic, but also for you and your brand
and your business. And as for Declan,
he's been with me in this room for
years. I've mentored him in business,
and a lot of conversations we have
offline,
I know that he's going to eventually want
to do his own thing.
And this trip back to the UK,
I used him less than ever.
I needed him less than ever.
I've seen the direction in
which content is going,
and I know that he wants to build his own
thing.
You've got about two or three years.
If you do not get a grip on all of this,
social media, content,
brand, email marketing, landing pages,
offer.
If you haven't got this nailed down in
three years,
you could be fucked.
So Declan knows there's a ticking time
bomb, and if he wants
to have his own mega brand, by the way,
you should follow him on YouTube and you
should definitely download his color
grading course for all of you YouTube
creators. He's aware that now's the time,
and I'm aware that I actually should be
doing more from my iPhone
and using him less.
So I just said to him, "Hey bro,
[phone clatters] do you want to go do your
own
thing?" He said,
"Yeah." I'm happy for him.
All the people that work for me should
quit eventually to do their own thing.
Because if I've hired people
that just want a salary for 20 years,
they may not be
the perfect audience for the person I'm
talking to on camera, nor for the advice
that I'm giving. And also,
if I'm a business coach,
you should spend a couple
months with me in a room
and be so gassed to start your own thing.
You should be quitting way quicker than
that. Even my fiancée, Tay.
I turned my back on her for a few months.
She's got her own online business selling
programs.
I went, "How did
that happen?" She came to my events,
listened to my advice.
What can I say?
If you want to work with me,
there's going to be a link in the
description.
But if you don't put out a piece of
short-form content every fucking day for
the
next three months, you
are thick as shit
and you're a fucking idiot.
Just like that guy with business cards
and a fucking T-shirt branded before he
even
fucking made videos for his own...
It's just stupid.
You can tell it's annoying.
The opportunity is there.
If you don't take it, someone else will,
and you'll be
the one fucking crying about it in a
couple years' time.
"Oh, but I'm a better coach than them,
but they've just got more followers." Play
the game, pussy.
My channel also recommends
that you're going to love this video
here if you've enjoyed the absolute
barrage of advice I just gave you then.
So click on that if you're not going to
buy my shit. Bye-bye.